PARTH KETAN DOSHI

parthketandoshi@gmail.com • Atlanta, GA - 30338 • +1(470)838-0620

linkedin.com/in/parthketandoshi • github.com/parthketandoshi • parthketandoshi.github.io • leetcode.com/parthketandoshi

SUMMARY

I am a Full-stack Software Engineer with 2+ years of professional experience in high-impact design, development and delivery of features in diverse software products. I am agile, curious, motivated and a self-starter. I am agile, curious, motivated and a self-starter. My experience in cross-functional teams has honed my ability to navigate through intricate issues and finding creative solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C, Java, Python, SQL, TypeScript

Technologies: Node, Angular, React, Bootstrap, Scss, Material UI, MongoDB, Spring Framework, Jenkins, AWS, Sonar, REST APIs **Concepts:** Data Structures, Algorithm Design, Object-oriented Design, Full-stack Web Development, Database Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Georgia State University

Atlanta, GA

Web Developer & Researcher

August 2022 onwards

- Gathered requirements and implemented end-to-end development and delivery of online platform for a distinguished professor
- Established pipelines to scrape reliable data sources, collect information and summarize it to cater doctoral candidates
- Employed AI to carry out extensive in-depth research on trends in digital business transformation and emerging technologies
- · Conducted weekly knowledge sharing, brainstorming and demo sessions on the research, its applications and prospects
- Published documentation on emerging technologies and contributed to innovative open-source projects through discussions

AVPS Technologies Inc

Alpharetta, GA

Software Engineer

May 2023 - September 2023

- Implemented UI frontend components, API microservices, backend data models and data dashboards for the products
- Refactored code base, undertook troubleshooting of bottlenecks, resolved issues and improved performance in the products
- Established fundamentals to provide custom experiences to end users across platforms based on preferences and personas
- Participated in scrum activities and advised adjustments to align with best software engineer practices and technical processes

Zycus Infotech Pvt Ltd

Mumbai, India

Associate Software Engineer, UI Centre of Excellence

January 2021 - August 2022

- Collaborated with product owners and members for 20+ product teams to analyze and deliver 80+ complex business requirements
- Developed 47+ responsive reusable components in **UI library** and 3 system analysis dashboards for monitoring and data reporting
- Liaised with UI/UX designers and leadership as Dev SPOC and audited adherence of products to WCAG 2.1 & ADA compliance
- Implemented the UI theme and 16+ components for a new app store platform and supported its integration in client products
- Upgraded the Language Management System handling translations for the suite in 16+ languages and migrated public dependencies
- Automated icon generation saving 12 hours and achieved Sonar rating of A for reliability, maintainability, scalability and security
- Groomed 8 resources through support channels and sessions and authored documentation on software development best practices
- Achieved individual recognition for agility, innovation and customer centricity in 2 core products and services

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCES

App Development Instructor, CampK12

April 2020 - May 2020

• Software Development Intern, Fube Technology

December 2018 - March 2019

• App Development Intern, Trivia Softwares

June 2018 - July 2018

• Web Development Intern, Toppr

February 2018 - July 2018

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCES

Teach for India

TAPtheTECH

Indian Society for Technical Education

Computer Society of India

EDUCATION

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Master of Science, Computer Information Systems, Digital Innovation, GPA - 4.0

Atlanta, GA August 2023

University of Mumbai

Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering, GPA - 3.0

October 2020

Certifications: Scrum Alliance - Certified Scrum Product Owner [®], SAFe POPM 5.1 Training, AWS Cloud Essentials

SELECTED ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Bridge Health Monitoring System - PWA, IoT, Sensors, Raspberry Pi, Python Libraries, Qt Framework, Firebase, Image & Audio Processing ● Social Media Platform - Angular, JSON APIs, Material UI ● Scribble Cloud - iOS automation script, NFC ● SpInput - Rotary Encoder, Arduino ● A11y (Ally) Token - Solana Blockchain, NFT ● Gujarati & Marathi News Classifier - NLP, Kaggle